<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>RILLA KHALED</title><link>https://rillakhaled.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on RILLA KHALED</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2022 13:46:29 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rillakhaled.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Sliders</title><link>https://rillakhaled.github.io/note/sliders/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2022 13:46:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rillakhaled.github.io/note/sliders/</guid><description>Today I am experimenting with:
CSS: overriding field input default styling, transitions, and transforms injecting regular HTML into Hugo size and color This is all style and no substance looking for a substantive home.
(Toggle away).</description></item><item><title>Games as Research</title><link>https://rillakhaled.github.io/project/games-as-research/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 16:02:46 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rillakhaled.github.io/project/games-as-research/</guid><description>Games as Research is an ongoing project I am undertaking primarily with Pippin Barr about documenting, observing, reflecting on, and learning from game design processes undertaken within an academic context.
Academic game design is a strange (low resolution) beast, falling somewhere between game studies and game HCI, but with special qualities that neither field adequately addresses, even when combined.
Our work is therefore about experimenting with and normalising design-oriented practices around game design research.</description></item><item><title>Prototyping ChaBoT</title><link>https://rillakhaled.github.io/note/prototyping-chabot/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 11:28:45 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rillakhaled.github.io/note/prototyping-chabot/</guid><description>For the last year or so, I&amp;rsquo;ve sporadically wondered about whether there would be any benefit to be gained by conducting a CBT-ish (structured? informed?) conversation with a non-human agent. CBT is highly structured and its activities frequently serve as therapy homework, i.e. you can do them on your own.
Talking to an agent obviously wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have the same effect as talking to a human therapist, on the other hand, what would the effect be?</description></item><item><title>Speculative Play</title><link>https://rillakhaled.github.io/project/speculative-play/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 10:37:02 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rillakhaled.github.io/project/speculative-play/</guid><description>What if we could make complex social and cultural questions playable? And what if we could do so through interactions with familiar digital interfaces set in alternative presents and near futures?
These questions constitute the backbone of the project, Speculative Play (funded by the Quebec FRQSC), which seeks to explore the intersection between the discursive design traditions of Speculative and Critical Design on the one hand, and the pragmatic philosophies and best practices of interaction design and playful media (PM) on the other.</description></item><item><title>restart()</title><link>https://rillakhaled.github.io/note/restart/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 10:15:10 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rillakhaled.github.io/note/restart/</guid><description>There always needs to be a first post, right?
This is that post.
Writing it evokes the eery sensation of sliding back into 1997.
Before CSS.
Before WordPress.
When size 8 courier was a badass typographical choice.
When complex layouts were painstakingly crafted from 0px border frames and 1px gifs.
When it still felt faintly plausible that you could, if you really worked at it, meet everyone in your country who happened to go online.</description></item></channel></rss>