<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>RILLA KHALED</title><link>https://rillakhaled.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on RILLA KHALED</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 09:42:07 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rillakhaled.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Splash of a Drop</title><link>https://rillakhaled.github.io/sketch/the-splash-of-a-drop/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 09:42:07 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rillakhaled.github.io/sketch/the-splash-of-a-drop/</guid><description>The Splash of a Drop The Splash of a Drop Images come from a publication from 1897 titled The Splash of a Drop by Professor A. M. Worthington. The publication is essentially lecture notes for a presentation he delivered, and it now exists within the public domain. The original features five pages of illustrations, collectively presenting 30 hand-drawn frames of a drop of mercury. Mouse over or touch for animation.</description></item><item><title>Words to Live By</title><link>https://rillakhaled.github.io/sketch/words-to-live-by/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 09:02:05 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rillakhaled.github.io/sketch/words-to-live-by/</guid><description>Words to Live By For years now, I've had a habit of falling asleep on the sofa around 9:30pm. The sleep comes on like a wave; it's closer to disappearing into unconsciousness. I awake about an hour later, and then out of a confused impulse to wreak revenge on myself for falling asleep too early, I proceed to stay up for another hour or two.</description></item><item><title>Being a JPG</title><link>https://rillakhaled.github.io/sketch/being-a-jpg/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 09:05:02 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rillakhaled.github.io/sketch/being-a-jpg/</guid><description> Being a JPG MP4 wishes to lead a simple life; dreams of being a JPG.</description></item><item><title>Productivity System</title><link>https://rillakhaled.github.io/sketch/productivity-system/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2022 13:24:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rillakhaled.github.io/sketch/productivity-system/</guid><description>Productivity System (Rilla's) Productivity System ((R)PS) No I don't mean that RPS. And I definitely don't mean this one (who even comes up with blockchain rock, paper, scissors??). Today, I have solved productivity. So now I am feeling extremely magnanimous; overflowing with benevolence in fact. And for today only I will share my productivity system with you freely. List your responsibilities / tasks / todos / obligations / burdens / millstones / peptic ulcer accelerants that are plaguing you.</description></item><item><title>A Box of Dad Jokes</title><link>https://rillakhaled.github.io/sketch/a-box-of-dad-jokes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 13:31:53 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rillakhaled.github.io/sketch/a-box-of-dad-jokes/</guid><description> Life is like a box of dad jokes Some of it is funny All of it is embarrassing Reload to get a fresh batch of dad jokes. Sound from ZapSplat.</description></item><item><title>The Actual AI Apocalypse</title><link>https://rillakhaled.github.io/note/the-actual-ai-apocalypse/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 14:23:17 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rillakhaled.github.io/note/the-actual-ai-apocalypse/</guid><description>The Actual AI Apocalypse The actual AI apocalypse will descend sluggishly and embarrassingly. The actual AI apocalypse will concern incremental wear-and-tear on one's reputation the type that is only possible with knowledge of what we really do, what we really think In the actual AI apocalypse, my OS will update my profile photos to photos I had "deleted"; email uncharitable things I said within range of Siri to my colleagues; submit all of my first drafts to conferences and journals; post private DM conversations in very public Discord channels; all of this silently, efficiently, inhumanly.</description></item><item><title>Unholy Unions: Merriam-Webster &amp; Giphy</title><link>https://rillakhaled.github.io/sketch/unholy-unions/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 08:50:13 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rillakhaled.github.io/sketch/unholy-unions/</guid><description> Unholy Unions: Merriam-Webster &amp; Giphy "If Merriam-Webster's Collegiate Dictionary and Giphy had a baby together, what would it look like?" Indeed. Well, now you can find out.</description></item><item><title>Machine Translation</title><link>https://rillakhaled.github.io/sketch/machine-translation/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 13:50:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rillakhaled.github.io/sketch/machine-translation/</guid><description>Machine Translation The vodka is good but the meat is rotten In the apocryphal machine translation story, the text "the spirit is willing but the flesh is weak" became, "the vodka is good but the meat is rotten".
Today's code sketch pays homage to that. Click on any of the words in the yellow box to see what WordsAPI rustles up as a synonym (no substitutions made means WordsAPI had no synonyms to offer).</description></item><item><title>SpaceTime</title><link>https://rillakhaled.github.io/sketch/space-time/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 10:32:01 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rillakhaled.github.io/sketch/space-time/</guid><description>Spacetime Where are we? During dinner the other day, our friend Jhave reminded us of the incredible difficulty of trying to retain in mind the idea that time is space. So consider the image a clock of sorts, that renders differently based on what time it is for you. Or where in the world you choose to be.</description></item><item><title>(300, 300)</title><link>https://rillakhaled.github.io/note/ghost-div/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 19:58:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rillakhaled.github.io/note/ghost-div/</guid><description>A well-known urban legend amongst front-end developers is the ghost div who haunts (300, 300).
They say that that div was put on the front page of www.geocities.com in 1999, at top: 300px; left: 300px;
It always rendered as fast as it could, positioned itself exactly where it was asked to, but because it had (accidentally?) been assigned a z-index of -999, none of the millions of people who frequented GeoCities back then ever noticed it or appreciated it.</description></item><item><title>Les Couleurs</title><link>https://rillakhaled.github.io/sketch/les-couleurs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 21:19:27 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rillakhaled.github.io/sketch/les-couleurs/</guid><description> Les Couleurs</description></item><item><title>Remember 1996?</title><link>https://rillakhaled.github.io/sketch/remember-1996/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 15:22:16 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rillakhaled.github.io/sketch/remember-1996/</guid><description> Remember 1996? i remember when only 8 people in the country made a living off of web design that country was New Zealand; "view source" felt like looking at the internet's undies.</description></item><item><title>That Sinking Feeling</title><link>https://rillakhaled.github.io/sketch/that-sinking-feeling/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rillakhaled.github.io/sketch/that-sinking-feeling/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Only Two</title><link>https://rillakhaled.github.io/sketch/only-two/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2022 12:32:46 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rillakhaled.github.io/sketch/only-two/</guid><description> Fast, cheap, good. This much is true. You can't have three, but you can have two. Other (common) cases no one bothers to mention: one | none.</description></item><item><title>Games as Research</title><link>https://rillakhaled.github.io/project/games-as-research/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 16:02:46 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rillakhaled.github.io/project/games-as-research/</guid><description>Games as Research is a SSHRC-funded project I am undertaking with Pippin Barr, Danny Godin, and Jonathan Lessard about documenting, observing, reflecting on, and learning from game design processes undertaken within an academic context.
Academic game design is a strange (low resolution) beast, falling somewhere between game studies and game HCI, but with special qualities that neither field adequately addresses, even when combined.
Our work is therefore about experimenting with and normalising design-oriented practices around game design research.</description></item><item><title>Prototyping ChaBoT</title><link>https://rillakhaled.github.io/note/prototyping-chabot/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 11:28:45 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rillakhaled.github.io/note/prototyping-chabot/</guid><description>For the last year or so, I&amp;rsquo;ve sporadically wondered about whether there would be any benefit to be gained by conducting a CBT-ish (structured? informed?) conversation with a non-human agent. CBT is highly structured and its activities frequently serve as therapy homework, i.e. you can do them on your own.
Talking to an agent obviously wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have the same effect as talking to a human therapist, on the other hand, what would the effect be?</description></item><item><title>Speculative Play</title><link>https://rillakhaled.github.io/project/speculative-play/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 10:37:02 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rillakhaled.github.io/project/speculative-play/</guid><description>What if we could make complex social and cultural questions playable? And what if we could do so through interactions with familiar digital interfaces set in alternative presents and near futures?
These questions constitute the backbone of the project, Speculative Play (funded by the Quebec FRQSC), which seeks to explore the intersection between the discursive design traditions of Speculative and Critical Design on the one hand, and the pragmatic philosophies and best practices of interaction design and playful media (PM) on the other.</description></item><item><title>restart()</title><link>https://rillakhaled.github.io/note/restart/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 10:15:10 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rillakhaled.github.io/note/restart/</guid><description>There always needs to be a first post, right?
This is that post.
Writing it evokes the eery sensation of sliding back into 1997.
Before CSS.
Before WordPress.
When size 8 courier was a badass typographical choice.
When complex layouts were painstakingly crafted from 0px border frames and 1px gifs.
When it still felt faintly plausible that you could, if you really worked at it, meet everyone in your country who happened to go online.</description></item></channel></rss>