<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>css on RILLA KHALED</title><link>https://rillakhaled.github.io/tags/css/</link><description>Recent content in css on RILLA KHALED</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 09:02:05 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rillakhaled.github.io/tags/css/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Words to Live By</title><link>https://rillakhaled.github.io/sketch/words-to-live-by/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 09:02:05 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rillakhaled.github.io/sketch/words-to-live-by/</guid><description>&lt;!DOCTYPE html> Words to Live By For years now, I've had a habit of falling asleep on the sofa around 9:30pm. The sleep comes on like a wave; it's closer to disappearing into unconsciousness. I awake about an hour later, and then out of a confused impulse to wreak revenge on myself for falling asleep too early, I proceed to stay up for another hour or two. I told my doctor about it, and her response to me was: "</description></item><item><title>Productivity System</title><link>https://rillakhaled.github.io/sketch/productivity-system/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2022 13:24:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rillakhaled.github.io/sketch/productivity-system/</guid><description>&lt;!DOCTYPE html> Productivity System (Rilla's) Productivity System ((R)PS) No I don't mean that RPS. And I definitely don't mean this one (who even comes up with blockchain rock, paper, scissors??). Today, I have solved productivity. So now I am feeling extremely magnanimous; overflowing with benevolence in fact. And for today only I will share my productivity system with you freely. List your responsibilities / tasks / todos / obligations / burdens / millstones / peptic ulcer accelerants that are plaguing you.</description></item><item><title>SpaceTime</title><link>https://rillakhaled.github.io/sketch/space-time/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 10:32:01 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rillakhaled.github.io/sketch/space-time/</guid><description> &lt;!DOCTYPE html> Spacetime Where are we? During dinner the other day, our friend Jhave reminded us of the incredible difficulty of trying to retain in mind the idea that time is space. So consider the image a clock of sorts, that renders differently based on what time it is for you. Or where in the world you choose to be. Also, who knew SVGs were so fun??</description></item><item><title>(300, 300)</title><link>https://rillakhaled.github.io/note/ghost-div/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 19:58:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rillakhaled.github.io/note/ghost-div/</guid><description>A well-known urban legend amongst front-end developers is the ghost div who haunts (300, 300).
They say that that div was put on the front page of www.geocities.com in 1999, at top: 300px; left: 300px;
It always rendered as fast as it could, positioned itself exactly where it was asked to, but because it had (accidentally?) been assigned a z-index of -999, none of the millions of people who frequented GeoCities back then ever noticed it or appreciated it.</description></item><item><title>Les Couleurs</title><link>https://rillakhaled.github.io/sketch/les-couleurs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 21:19:27 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rillakhaled.github.io/sketch/les-couleurs/</guid><description> &lt;!DOCTYPE html> Les Couleurs</description></item><item><title>Remember 1996?</title><link>https://rillakhaled.github.io/sketch/remember-1996/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 15:22:16 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rillakhaled.github.io/sketch/remember-1996/</guid><description>&lt;!DOCTYPE html> Remember 1996? i remember when only 8 people in the country made a living off of web design that country was New Zealand; "view source" felt like looking at the internet's undies.</description></item><item><title>That Sinking Feeling</title><link>https://rillakhaled.github.io/sketch/that-sinking-feeling/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rillakhaled.github.io/sketch/that-sinking-feeling/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Only Two</title><link>https://rillakhaled.github.io/sketch/only-two/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2022 12:32:46 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rillakhaled.github.io/sketch/only-two/</guid><description> Fast, cheap, good. This much is true. You can't have three, but you can have two. Other (common) cases no one bothers to mention: one | none.</description></item><item><title>restart()</title><link>https://rillakhaled.github.io/note/restart/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 10:15:10 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rillakhaled.github.io/note/restart/</guid><description>There always needs to be a first post, right?
This is that post.
Writing it evokes the eery sensation of sliding back into 1997.
Before CSS.
Before WordPress.
When size 8 courier was a badass typographical choice.
When complex layouts were painstakingly crafted from 0px border frames and 1px gifs.
When it still felt faintly plausible that you could, if you really worked at it, meet everyone in your country who happened to go online.</description></item></channel></rss>